singaporebikes.com 2016-10-07

# Welcome to SingaporeBikes.com - Where Singaporean Bikers Unite!

##### Your privacy is important to us. This Data Protection Policy outlines how your Personal Data will be managed in accordance with the Personal Data Protection Act (“PDPA”) which strives to protect personal data of individuals. Please take a moment to read this Data Protection Policy so that you know and understand the purposes for which we may collect, use and/or disclose your Personal Data.

You agree and consent to SingaporeBikes (referred herein as “SingaporeBikes” , “us”, “we” or “our”) as well as our respective agents and staff, collecting, using, disclosing and/or sharing your Personal Data in the manner set forth in this Data Protection Policy.

#####   
This Data Protection Policy supplements but does not supersede nor replace any other consents which you may have previously provided to us nor does it affect any rights that we may have at law in connection with the collection, use and/or disclosure of your Personal Data. We may from time to time update this Data Protection Policy to ensure that this Data Protection Policy is consistent with our future developments, industry trends and/or any changes in legal or regulatory requirements.

For the avoidance of doubt, this Data Protection Policy forms a part of the terms and conditions governing your relationship with us and should be read in conjunction with such terms and conditions (“Terms and Conditions”). In the event of any conflict or inconsistency between the provisions of this Data Protection Policy and the Terms and Conditions, the provisions of the Terms and Conditions shall prevail.

1.    Your Personal Data  
        In this Data Protection Policy, “Personal Data” refers to any data or information about you from which you can be identified either (a) from that data; or (b) from that data and other information to which we have or are likely to have access.

##### Examples of such Personal Data include:

#####        (a)    your name, telephone number(s), mailing address, email address and any other information relating to you which you have provided us in any forms you may have submitted to us, or in other forms of interaction with you;

#####        (b)   information about your use of SingaporeBikes' website and services, including cookies and IP addresses;

#####        (c)   your transaction related information, such as your paypal login ID; and

#####        (e)   information about your usage of and interaction with our website and/or services including computer and connection information, device capability, bandwidth, statistics on page views, and traffic to and from our website.

##### 2.    Collection of Personal Data

##### 2.1   Generally, SingaporeBikes may collect your Personal Data in the following ways: 

#####        (a)   when you register with us for an account;

#####        (b)   when you access our website or perform an online transaction;

#####        (c)   when you interact with any of our employees (including mechanics);

#####        (d)   when you respond to our request for additional Personal Data; 

#####        (e)   when you ask to be included in an email or other mailing list; 

#####        (f)    when you request that we contact you;

#####        (g)   when you respond to our initiatives or promotions; and 

#####        (h)   when you submit your Personal Data to us for any other reason. 

##### 2.2   When you browse our website, you generally do so anonymously, but please see section 6 below on cookies.

##### 3.    Purposes for the Collection, Use and Disclosure of Your Personal Data

##### 3.1   Generally, SingaporeBikes may collect, use and/or disclose your Personal Data for the following purposes:

#####        (a)   evaluating and providing advice and/or recommendations to you regarding the type of products and services suited to your needs;

#####        (b)   assessing and processing any applications or requests made by you for products and services offered by us;

#####        (c)   communicating with you to inform you of changes and updates to our  policies, terms and conditions and other administrative information, including without limitation for the purposes of servicing you in relation to products and services offered to you;

#####        (d)   administering, maintaining, managing and operating the products and services offered to you;

#####        (e)   verification of your identity for the purpose of providing you with our services;

#####        (f)    responding to your queries and requests and handling complaints;

#####        (g)   conducting market research for statistical profiling and other purposes to understand and determine customer preferences and demographics in order for us to review, develop and improve the products and services which we are providing to you (including without limitation to ensure that the products and services offered are relevant to you);

#####        (h)   conducting financial reporting and analysis related to our business operations;

#####        (i)    managing our infrastructure and business operations and complying with internal policies and procedures; 

#####        (j)    archival of documents and records in both electronic and physical form for record keeping purposes;

#####        (k)   maintaining records of customer instructions, whether through phone recordings, hard copy documents, soft copy documents or instructions given via electronic or other means;

#####        (l)  conducting credit checks and ensuring your ongoing creditworthiness, and the collection of amounts outstanding from you and any person providing security or guarantees for your obligations;

#####        (m)  any other purpose directly relating to any of the above.

##### 4.    Marketing / Optional Purposes 

##### 4.1   Where you have specifically provided us with additional consents, SingaporeBikes may also collect, use and/or disclose your Personal Data for the following purposes:

#####        (a)   providing benefits to you, including without limitation promotions, loyalty and reward programmes and sending you details of products, services, special offers and rewards, either to our customers generally, or which may be of interest to you; 

#####        (b)   matching your Personal Data with other data collected for other purposes and from other sources (including third parties) in connection with the provision or offering of products and services, whether by us, or other third parties; 

#####        (c)   fulfilling your referral requests;       

#####        (d)   administering contests and competitions;        

#####        (e)   participation in our marketing initiatives;

#####        (f)    participation in our branding activities (including without limitation written or video/audio recordings of your quotes and testimony

#####        (g)   invitations to participate in our events & activities, and the image/video/audio recording of your feedback and testimony in relation thereto; and

#####        (h)   developing special offers and marketing programmes. If you have provided your Singapore telephone number(s) and have indicated that you consent to receiving marketing or promotional information via your Singapore telephone number(s), then from time to time, we may contact you using such Singapore telephone number(s) (including via voice calls, SMS, fax or other means) with information about our products and services (including discounts and special offers). 

##### 5.    Disclosure of Personal Data 

##### 5.1   Personal Data will be protected and kept confidential but, subject to the provisions of any applicable law, may be disclosed for the purposes listed above (where applicable) to the following parties: 

#####        (a)   companies providing services relating to insurance and/or reinsurance to HSBC;

#####        (b)   insurance surveyors, private investigators, hospitals or clinics in connection with claims or underwriting assessment;

#####        (c)   associations of insurance companies & hire purchase institutions

#####        (d)   agents, contractors or third party service providers who provide services, such as telecommunications, call centre, mailing, information technology, payment, payroll, data processing, training, market research, storage and archival, to SingaporeBikes

#####        (e)   the Credit Bureau, or in the event of default or disputes, any debt collection agencies or dispute resolution centres (whether in Singapore or otherwise)

#####        (f)  any liquidator, receiver, official assignee / trustee, judicial manager or any other person appointed under or pursuant to any applicable law or court order in connection with the bankruptcy, liquidation, winding up, judicial management or any other analogous process in respect of any individual, company or business;

#####        (g)   our professional advisers such as our auditors and lawyers;

#####        (h)   any judicial, administrative or regulatory body, any government or public orgovernment agency, instrumentality or authority, court, or law enforcement body or any agents thereof

#####        (i)    operators of payment systems, such as the Network for Electronic Transfers (Singapore) Pte Ltd & Paypal in connection with any payments, charges or other related instructions you may issue

#####        (j)  third party reward, loyalty, privileges and co-branding programme providers;

#####        (k)   co-branding partners of SingaporeBikes (the names of such co-branding partners will be provided during the application of the relevant services and products, as the case may be); and

#####        (q)   any other person in connection with the purposes set forth above.

##### 6.    Use of cookies 

##### 6.1   We may collect or analyse anonymised information from which individuals cannot be identified (“Aggregate Information”), such as number of users and their frequency of use, the number of page views (or page impressions) that occur on our websites and common entry and exit points into our website. 

##### 6.2   We use “cookies”, where a small data file is sent to your browser to store and track Aggregate Information about you when you enter our websites. The cookie is used to track information such as the number of users and their frequency of use, profiles of users and their preferred sites.

##### 6.3   The Aggregate Information collected is used to assist us in analysing the usage of our websites and improving our websites. 

##### 6.4   Should you wish to disable the cookies associated with these technologies, you may do so by changing the setting on your browser. However, you may not be able to enter certain part(s) of our websites. 

##### 7.    Third-Party Sites 

#####        Our website may contain links to other websites operated by third parties. We are not responsible for your use and access of such links and for the privacy practices of websites operated by third parties that are linked to our website. We encourage you to learn about the privacy policies of such third party websites. Some of these third party websites may be co-branded with our logo or trademark, even though they are not operated or maintained by us. Once you have left our website, you should check the applicable data protection policy of the third party to determine how they will handle any information they collect from you. 

##### 8.    Withdrawal of Consent

#####        If you wish to withdraw your consent to any use or disclosure of your Personal Data as set out in this Data Protection Policy, you may contact us via our contact number. Please note that if you withdraw your consent to any or all use or disclosure of your Personal Data, depending on the nature of your request, we may not be in a position to continue to provide our products or services to you or administer any contractual relationship in place. Such withdrawal may also result in the termination of any agreement you may have with us. 

##### 9.    Access and Correction of your Personal Data 

#####        You may request access to or make corrections to your Personal Data records, but SingaporeBikes has the right to charge a reasonable fee for processing your request. Please submit your request to our staff via contact for us to proceed. 

##### 10.   Contacting Us

#####        If you have any questions or complaints relating to the use or disclosure of your Personal Data, or if you wish to know more about our data protection policies and practices, please contact us directly via our contact us page
